《越狱》第四季 第七集
Prison.Break.S04E07
《越狱》剧情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
这些是踝部GPS监视器
These are GPS ankle monitors.
大家都过来  每个人都戴上一个
Now,step up,take one and put it on.
交换人质结束后
When the exchange is over,
我和你要好好的算一下帐
you and I are gonna spend some quality time.
这些不是释放文件
These aren't release papers.
我尽了全力了
I did the best I could do.
你只有签了名  我才能拿到罗兰的仪器
You need to sign those so I can collect Roland's device.
你想让我放弃
You want me to give up the one thing
我在这个小组中唯一存在的价值
that makes me valuable to the team.
你清楚你入伙的时候  我们的君子协定
Hey,you knew the deal when you came onboard.
你以为  你走错一步
Do you want to flush it down the toilet
你还能拍拍屁股走人吗
because you made a bad move?
这个人刚刚继承了10万美金的遗产
This man just came into a $100,000 inheritance.
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
如果你见到他  可以给我们打个电话吗
If you do see him,would you please give us a call?
你不在税务局工作
You don't work for the IRS?
我不在
I don't.
你为谁卖命
Who do you work for?
现在  我只为我自己
As of now... myself.
我是克兰兹将军的助手
I'm an associate of General Krantz.
将军喜欢保留自己的隐私
The general,he likes his privacy.
我开始就知道你不是个正经的销售员
I knew you were rotten from the beginning,
我要你彻底交代清楚
so I want you to walk me through this
如果你说不清楚  我就向当局报告
and if you can't,I'm gonna call the authorities.
科尔・普发
Cole Pfeiffer.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
上一次
The last time
一个像你一样的小姑娘
a pretty little filly like yourself
把我打晕还五花大绑在椅子上
knocked me senseless and tied me to a chair,
我是付了钱给她的
I had to pay for it.
这次你或许也可以故技重演啊
You still might.
那本书是我一个最亲近的朋友
That book was a gift
送给我的礼物
from a very dear friend of mine
他很突然地就去世了
who left this realm all too soon.
詹姆斯・惠斯勒只会给别人
The only thing that James Whistler ever gave anybody
送去淋病
was the clap.
你有30秒时间告诉我
You have 30 seconds to tell me something
一些我不知道的事情
that I don't already know.
我和詹姆斯・惠斯勒关在巴拿马的时候
I followed that book from Panama City,
就一直留意这本书  根据书的内容
where James Whistler and I were co-incarcerated,
我找到了一个在圣地亚哥车站的柜子
to a bus locker in San Diego.
在里面有关于这栋公寓
Inside was information pertaining to this apartment...
是锡拉
Scylla.
怎么样
How about that?
听起来很熟悉吧
That ring a bell,huh? Huh?
你知道多少关于锡拉的事情
What do you know about Scylla?
我只知道我是最关键的人物
I know I'm holding the keys,
没有我  那本书
because without me,that bird book's
连一点意义都没有
about as meaningful as a fart in a wind storm.
我使用了惠斯勒的化名
I commandeered Whistler's alias.
我混进了他工作的地方
I infiltrated his place of business
因为那是揭开所有谜团的钥匙
because it's the gateway to the whole damn thing.
地点在哪
Where's the location?
你怎么着也得给我点好处甜头吧
What do you bring to the jamboree,darling,huh?
除了蓝色的小上衣
Aside from those baby blues
和一把刀
and a knife?
这是我
This is me.
这是锡拉
This is Scylla.
这是你
This is you.
我一定会得到锡拉
I am gonna get Scylla.
区别只是那时你可能还活着
And it can either be with you...
也可能已经死翘翘了
...or through you.
所以  为什么你不能
So why don't you give me
在我割下你的睾丸前
that informed decision right now,
告诉我你考虑后的答案呢
before I spill your hillbilly guts all over the carpet?
你别想和我耍花样
'Cause you're messing with the wrong bitch.
我能为你做些什么呢
How may I be of service?
真不敢相信
This is unbelievable.
我们还在考虑怎么跟踪斯库得利
We were planning our move
-他竟然包了整架飞机  -对
on Scuderi when he chartered the flight. Right.
而且你不能先一步知道
And no chance you dragged your feet a little bit
斯库得利包了整架飞机
waiting for Scuderi to charter the flight?
对  我们故意晚了一步
Oh,yeah,we want to drag this out.
地点不错  你觉得呢　林肯
Yeah,well,location's pretty convenient,wouldn't you say,Linc?
既然斯库得利出城了
Uh,Scuderi splitting town
那我们是不是可以休息一下了
kind of caught us a break,huh?
你能不能让他闭嘴
Would you shut him up?
别这样对我
No,no.
我们不能就这样等他回来
SELF: We could just wait till he comes back.
昂格里逊公司制造农业用化学物质
AgriSow makes farm chemicals.
又不是军事基地
It's not Fort Knox.
你敢打赌吗
You want to bet?
他们的专利价值上亿
Their patents are worth billions.
所以很多公司都对这些专利
Which is why companies tend to keep a very close eye
非常关注
on those patents.
我们在一个星期内
Yeah,we could breach their security,
可以突破他们的保安系统  我们也可以
in a week,minimum. We could get
在一个星期内进入他的房子
in the guy's house-- week,minimum.
或者跟踪他12个小时
Or we could follow the guys for 12 hours out of town
在午夜之前得到第五张卡  你觉得怎么样
and have card five by midnight. How's that sound?
你们觉得这个主意如何
How does this sound?
如果你们半夜之前回不来  全都给我蹲大狱
If you're not back by midnight you're going to jail.
你以为我不知道
Yeah,don't I know it.
我们出去谈谈
Let's talk outside.
那我们该怎么打算呢
So what's the plan?
我们去拉斯维加斯
We're going to Vegas.
好极了
Oh,hell yes!
我要霰弹枪
Yo,I call shotgun!
你们谁有...
Huh? Who's got-- Hey.
你想和我谈什么  赛尔夫探员
So what do you want to talk about,Agent Self?
到现在 我已经参与了
I've been a part of hundreds
不下于几百次的行动了
of operations during my career--
我告诉你一件事
and I'll tell you one thing.
我从来没有被人列为第一追杀目标
I never been on the top of someone else's hit list.
-你什么意思  -我什么意思
What are you talking about? What am I talking about?
如果这个叫怀特的公司杀手能找到我一次
If this Company hit man Wyatt
那他下次突然出现在我车后面
can find me once,it's only a matter of time
只不过是时间问题
until he creeps up in the back of my rearview mirror again.
这不可能
Well,that's not true.
如果他要干掉你
'Cause you'll never see him coming at all
你不可能见他第二次
if he's coming after you. Yeah.
这话挺安慰我的
That's comforting.
你以为呢  我想你死吗
What do you think,I want that?
你死了 我们都得回监狱
You're dead,we're all back in jail.
你当特工的时间比我长
You were an agent longer than me.
我现在该如何是好呢
What's my play here?
我和你直说了吧  你把我留在看守所里
Let me get this straight. You turn your back
现在你问我你该如何是好
on me and now you want to know my play
那是你的错
That was your fault.
你尽职尽责了吗?
What would you have done?
我追踪的人都是强奸犯  杀人犯
I've tracked down rapists,killers,
退役军人
even former military,
但是一个结构工程师就把我搞定了
but a structural engineer from Illinois was able to get to me.
你知道为什么吗
Want to know how?
告诉我
Yeah,I want to know.
他没有逃跑
He stopped running.
他主动出击
He got aggressive.
我反倒成了他游戏的玩偶
He took the game to me.
你就该学学他的手段
That's your play.
你只有背水一战这条路了
That's your only play.
我不用提醒你  谋杀一个联邦探员
I shouldn't have to remind you that killing a federal agent
是非常麻烦的  就算为了工作也是一样
is a complicated matter-- even in our line of work.
也许  马宏只不过是
Perhaps Mahone is just
冰山一角
the tip of the iceberg.
我们一直在搜寻
We've been searching for the link between
重型监狱　布伦斯和斯科菲尔德之间的联系
SuperMax and Burrows and Scofield.
我相信我们已经找到联系了
I believe we found it.
如果斯科菲尔德和布伦斯已和政府联手
If Scofield and Burrows are working with the government,
我们惹上的麻烦可比一个
we've got a much bigger problem
国土安全局的小探员更大了
than one bureaucrat at Homeland Security.
但是  是那个小探员带的头
But it begins with that bureaucrat.
如果当・赛尔夫是他们的头
And if Don Self is the head of the snake...
让他看上去是死于意外
Make it look like an accident.
顺便说一下  我的费用得翻一倍
My fee just doubled,by the way.
喂
Hello?
是布拉德吗
Uh,hi,is this Brad?
是的
Yeah.
几天前  你来我办公室
Uh,you came by my office a couple of days ago
找一个继承遗产的人
looking for a guy who had an inheritance coming to him.
是的
Right.
我知道他在哪
I know where he is.
她先要两千
She wants two grand first.
我中午和她见面
I'm meeting her at noon.
但是下一张卡更重要  对吧
Okay,the next card's more important,right?
我们先去维加斯  然后再解决蒂博格
So Vegas first,then we deal with T-Bag.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我留下来
I'll stay.
好吧
All right.
林肯  带着
Linc,take,uh,
莎拉  苏克雷
Sara and Sucre...
罗兰　去维加斯
...Roland to Vegas.
我们留下来的
The rest of us...
会解决蒂博格
...will handle T-Bag
大家都听到了  我们上路吧
You heard the man,let's go.
你得答应我一些事  好吗
...promise me something,would you?
说
Yeah.
你能帮我弄张俺媳妇滴照片吗
Can you get me Carrot Top's autograph?
我只是觉得
'Cause I just think
这样才能让我无怨无悔地放手去干
that would make this whole thing worthwhile.
多加小心
Be safe.
维加斯宝贝儿  我们来咯!
Ay,yo,Vegas,bitches!
他应该得到线索了
He should have the info by now.
贝里克怎么去了这么长时间
Okay,what the hell's taking Bellick so long?
她想要更多的钱
BELLICK: She wants more money.
多少钱
How much more?
我不知道
I don't know.
你得过来和她谈谈
You got to come talk to this chick.
别动
Hold on,hold on.
怎么了　贝里克
What's going on,Bellick?
面对现实吧
Believe it.
出什么事了 布拉德
What happened,Brad?
对不起  我没看出来是个圈套
Sorry,guys,I walked right into it,too.
没关系  动作快点
It's okay. Go. Go! Come on,now!
你根本不清楚你在跟谁合作  伙计
You have no idea who you're working with,honey.
只有一个了断的法子  蒂博格
There's only one way this can end,Bagwell.
你能不能别搞那么多花样
Why don't we skip the theatrics
直接告诉我们你想要什么
and you just tell us what you want.
我非常愿意让你头上开花
I'd love to put a hole right in your head.
没时间了
Time's up.
他也是
Him,too.
全部给我上车
Let's all get in the van.
现在 全部给我上车
Let's all get in the van now.
马宏  你也上去
You,too,Mahone.
我还记得我们初识的那一天  小白脸
I remember the day we met,Pretty.
你坐在长凳上
You were a scared little college boy
好像一个胆小如鼠的文弱书生
sittin' up on those bleachers,
试着不招惹麻烦
tryin' to keep your ass out of the game.
现在再看看你
Now look at you.
冷酷  无情
Cold. Hard.
好像一朵需要
Like a dried up flower
浇灌的花朵
wanting to get watered.
告诉我你想要什么
Just tell me what you want.
我想让你受尽折磨
I want to make you bleed.
我想让我体内被封印多年的心魔
I want to release the sinner inside of me
再一次苏醒
that got me incarcerated so many years ago.
但是  这一次
But it seems
你很走运  小白脸
you caught yourself a break,Pretty.
我需要你
I need you.
现在
Now...
你要乖乖地和我合作
you gonna cooperate right quick or so help me
否则  我会打到你站不起来
I'm gonna stomp you till you can't stand.
看着这几页
The pages-- look at them.
-看着像地图  是不是 -我不知道
Looks like some kind of map,right? I don't know.
你不知道的话  不可能一直
You know enough to chase me down
追着我到这里
looking for this.
别对我撒谎  小白脸
Now don't lie to me,Pretty.
不管书里有什么  都不是你和我能解决的问题
Whatever's in that book-- it is bigger than you and me.
就和锡拉一样
What,like Scylla big?
这不是游戏
This is not a game,Theodore.
你得告诉我  你一直和谁联络
Now,you need to tell me who you've been talking to.
我不需要听你的鬼话
I don't need to do a damn thing.
这就是所谓枪杆子里出政权了
That's the benefit of being the man with the gun.
你现在给我写下
You're going to write down everything
你知道所有关于锡拉的事情
you already know about Scylla,
还有所有你从书里看到东西
and everything you learn from that book...
否则  我就让墙上
...or I'm going to paint these walls
沾满你的脑浆
with your gray matter.
开工了!
Get to work!
[档案名: 康姆利集团]
The Comrie Group
好的  我马上就到
All right. I'll be right there.
赛尔夫
Self.
自从联系后
Hey. Michael's position
迈克的位置一直没变
hasn't changed since you called.
我们怎么知道他没有....
How do we know he...?
蒂博格是个神经病
Bagwell's a psychopath,
但是他是有计划的
but he's a psychopath with a plan.
很明显  他需要从迈克那里得到什么
He obviously needs something from Michael,
只要迈克不给他
and as long as Michael doesn't give it to him,
他就能活着
he'll keep breathing.
好吧  我和你一起去
All right. I'm coming with you.
不  不  我能搞定
No,no,no,no. I got it.
计划不变
Stick to the plan.
你会忘记玛丽克鲁兹吗
Will you forget about Maricruz?
你认为她不知道
You think she didn't know
她姐姐要把你供出去吗
her sister was trying to set you up,man?
你最好在维加斯有所斩获  兄弟
You better get some ass in Vegas,bro.
我们是来复制卡的
We're here to copy the card.
然后就离开  明白吗
Then we leave. Got it?
你得到迈克的消息了吗
Have you heard from Michael?
没有  怎么了?
No. Why?
没事  我要快点搞定这个任务
Nothing. I want this thing done.
维加斯决不是久留之地
Vegas ain't my town.
真是个傻子  是吧
What a fool,huh?
怎么会有人不爱这个地方呢
How could anyone not love this place,right?
看看这些画面  就在那
Check this out. Right there.
那个亚洲人
The Asian guy.
我好像在哪见过他
I know I've seen him someplace before.
弄得怎么样了?
So what do you have for me?
伽特是什么
So what's "GATE"?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
在那个盒子上写着呢
It's on that box.
-你为什么想知道呢  -只是好奇
Why do you want to know? Just curious.
假如我要告诉你
What if I was to tell you
我认为你只是在拖延时间呢
I think you're just stalling?
拖延时间  直到你可以想出一条妙计
Biding time till you can figure out some MacGyver way
-离开这儿  是吧  -我告诉你  你在用枪
to get your ass out of here,huh? I'd say you've got that gun
指着能够帮助你的人
pointed at the one person who can help you.
所以何不停止浪费我的时间呢
So why don't you stop wasting my time?
求求你  别让他伤害我
Please,don't let him!
她怎么样啊?
她怎么样  迈克?
How 'bout her,Michael?
能给个我不必杀她的理由吗
Any reason why I shouldn't kill her?
让我们测验一下吧
Let's do a test.
不!
No!
进展到什么程度了　迈克・斯科菲尔德?
How far gone is Michael Scofield?
迈克  他想知道什么就告诉他吧
Michael,just tell him what he wants!
进展到什么程度了  迈克・斯科菲尔德
How far gone is Michael Scofield?!
求你了  别让他杀我  求你了
Please,don't let him. Please!
迈克  你啥时候变了个人似的了?
When did it happen,Michael?
求你了  别让他杀了我
Please,don't let him...
你啥时候开始不关心伤害别人的事了啊?
When did you stop caring about hurting people,huh?
福克斯河监狱?  还是索纳监狱?
Fox River? Sona?
你要在子弹穿透她的脑袋时
You gonna keep dragging
选择视而不见吗
your feet while I put a bullet in her brain?
你为何不把枪放下
Why don't you put that gun down.
帅哥  你开始动笔的时候我就会把枪放下了!
I'll put it down when you start writing down,Pretty!
最后的机会  三
Last chance. Three!
二  一
Two! One...
我说  我说
All right! All right!
这些纸  是要拼在一起的
The pages,they fit together.
但是它不是个地图
But it's not a map.
是一张设计图
It's a blueprint.
什么设计图
For what?
我们的朋友贝里克  戴着
Our friend,Bellick,is wearing
一个政府发的脚踝监视器
a government-issued ankle monitor.
我猜斯科菲尔德也有一个
My guess is that Scofield has one,too.
我就知道那个贱人在拖延时间
I knew that son of a bitch was slow-walking me.
任何时候  联邦官员都有可能
Any minute,federal agents could come
破门而入
blasting through that door.
那我们该怎么办?
So what do we do?
我要你弄到那个监视器的生产资料和序列号
I need you to get the make and serial number of that monitor.
放松一点  振作精神  戴茜小姐
Feel free to pitch in here,Miss Daisy.
如果让斯科菲尔德知道我卷入其中就完了
If Scofield knows I'm involved,this is over.
我们需要他的帮助
We need to keep him on point.
现在  你出去把线索找出来
Now,get out there and get that information.
那些特工怎么办
What about the agents?
兵来将挡
Let 'em come.
我们怎么知道他会出来赌博
How do we even know this guy's out gambling?
那家伙有30万美元的信用额度  还有免费的客房
The guy's got $300,000 in credit and a comped room.
他就在这里  继续找下去
He's here. Keep looking.
莎拉
Hey,Sara.
我知道现在不是谈这个话题的最佳时机
Hey,uh,I realize this might not be the best time for this,
但迈克还没给我打过电话
but I still haven't heard from Michael.
他们正在解决蒂博格吧
They must be dealing with T-Bag.
-林肯  别这样  -什么
Lincoln,come on. What?
维加斯不是你的地盘
Vegas just isn't your town?
任何你告诉我的事
From everything I've heard about you,
都可能极大地改变进程
that would be a pretty big change of pace.
我也这么想
I guess so.
林肯  告诉我好吗
Lincoln,please talk to me.
迈克有和你说过妈妈的事情吗
Has Michael told you about Mom?
没有
No.
他们很像
They were much alike.
有着同样的想法
They got the same mind.
当妈妈变老的时候  她开始失去意识
As Mom got older,she started to lose it.
我们后来才知道
We,uh,later found out
这是脑瘤的征兆
it was a symptom of a brain tumor,hama...
错构瘤
Hamartoma. Yeah.
她小时候  经常流鼻血
As a kid,she got nosebleeds.
后来不留鼻血了
They stopped.
当她30岁的时候  又开始流了
In her 30s,they started up again.
她后来死于动脉瘤
She later died of a brain aneurysm.
你告诉我这些  是想让我知道
And you're telling me this,because Michael and his mother
迈克和他妈妈有一样的症状  对吗
are similar in that way,too,right?
他小时候也流鼻血的
He got nosebleeds as a kid.
后来也不流了  但几天前
They stopped,and the last couple of days
他又开始了
they started up again.
你妈妈几岁时候过世的
How old was your mom when she passed away?
31岁
Thirty-one.
迈克刚刚31岁啊
Michael's just turned 31.
我找到他了
I found him.
盯着他
Keep an eye on him.
好的
Okay.
你是安德鲁・布劳纳吗
Andrew Blauner?
恩  是的
Uh,yeah.
有什么可以为您效劳的吗
Can I help you?
希望可以
I hope so.
我想知道你有没有男朋友或者室友之类的
Any boyfriends or roommates I should know about?
没有
No.
今天有预定外卖吗
Any deliveries scheduled for today?
没有
No.
我再给你一次
I'm giving you one more...
这些都是什么啊
What is all this?
你还好吗
You okay?
他们让我别和你说话
They told me not to talk to you.
他们?  他们是谁?
"They"? Who's they?
这是惠斯勒的设计图
This is Whistler's blueprint.
我们可以在这个建筑里找到锡拉
It's the building where we can find Scylla.
换句话说就是在伽特公司里
In other words,it's GATE.
锡拉在哪
Where's Scylla?
我在看到楼之前不能确定
I can't be certain until I see the building itself,
但是我确定就在办公室下面的某个地方
but I'm pretty sure it's somewhere down here,below this office.
什么是锡拉
What is Scylla?
是公司的小黑名单
It's The Company's little black book.
我想你现在就带我去伽特公司
I want you to take me to GATE,now.
因为你能从锡拉里嗅出钱的味道　是吧
Because you can smell that Scylla money,can't you?
那就是你为什么参加的原因　就像我一样
That's what you're in it for,just like me.
说出来
Say it.
说吧
Come on.
我想你说出来
I want you to say it.
我加入是为了钱
I'm in it for the money.
你看到了
You see?
我们其实没什么区别
We ain't so different after all.
说
Yes?
当・赛尔夫不在家
Don Self is not at his house.
看起来他跑路了
Looks like he cleared out.
通知局里我们的手下还有洛城警方
Notify our people inside the Bureau and LAPD.
我觉得他跑不了多远
I doubt that he could have gotten very far.
长官
Sir?
现在不行
Not now.
当・赛尔夫要见你
Don Self is here to see you.
提个醒  朋友　她性冷淡
Got to warn you,friend,she's cold.
[数据卡存储空间已满  请清理或更换磁卡]
[短信: 设备故障  撤]
祝你好运　伙计
Good luck,pal.
盯着他
Stay with him.
斯科菲尔德就在那里
Scofield's really getting somewhere in there.
效率挺高的嘛
Man works fast.
他说如果看不到我以前在哪工作的
Says he can't get any further
就无法进展下去
without seeing my former place of employment.
你把我们的绊脚石处理掉了吗
Did you take care of our little troll problem?
想都别想对我干这种事
Don't even think about doing this to me.
你可不能过河拆桥甩了我啊
My name's on the door.
要不是我觉得你还有利用价值
If I didn't think you were valuable,
你早就死翘翘了
you'd be dead already.
这只是有点信息超载  伙计们
It's-It's just a little sensory overload,guys.
只是卡上没有空间了
There just wasn't any room for the card.
不错 因为如果我们把装置打开
Right. Because if we turn the device on
它就把赌场里所有的卡上信息都收集来了
in the casino,it fills up on all the data from the slots.
就像他们付账的时候
Like when they're about to pay out.
-这绝对不是预料之中的　-是吗
Oh,it's completely unintentional. Really?
是的　这不就是你造这玩意儿的初衷吗
Yeah. It's not why you built the damn thing in the first place?
如果我们不需要你
If we didn't need you...
可你们需要我　我们从长计议  好吗
But you do,so just take a brewski and chill,all right?
我们要想个办法让斯库得利一个人待着
Okay,we need to figure out a way to get Scuderi alone.
喂
Yeah.
老男人在水池边出现了
The old man just showed up at the pool.
从他穿着来看
From what he's wearing,there's no way
他身上不可能有卡
he's got the card on him.
跟着他
Stay with him.
卡在他房里
Card's in his room.
告诉我  唐纳德
Tell me,Donald,
你臆想中我们碰头的这一刻会是怎样一番景象呢
how did you play this moment out in your head?
你想到你自己会过来吗
Did you picture yourself coming in here,
昂首挺胸  盛气凌人地
chest out,jaw squared,
准备让我给你答案
ready to demand answers?
你可曾在幻想中想过
Did you at any time in your fantasy
你会这么紧张呢
imagine that you would be this nervous?
老实说 我从前没想过
Honestly,I,uh... I didn't think much past
把这些东西给你
giving you these.
柏林　尼日利亚
Berlin. Nigeria.
康姆利集团
The Comrie Group.
怎么不把肯尼迪遇刺
Why not JFK
和林德伯格绑架案也一块儿搞来?
and the Lindbergh baby while you're at it?
孩子
Son,
这些事情都已经调查完毕了
those matters have been fully vetted.
都是些陈年往事了
They're relics.
我跟这些一点关系都没有
I had nothing to do with them,and if
如果这些是你调查我的原因
this is why you've been pulling data on me,
我可以省你不少麻烦呢
I could have saved you a lot of trouble.
好吧　这些记录
Okay. Well,these records
和足以解释我调查你涉嫌参与这些事件原因
and a sealed letter explaining my investigation
的这封密封的信
into your involvement with these matters
已被送到了国内五位律师手中
was sent to five lawyers across the country.
万一我遇到什么不测
If anything happens to me,
万一我失踪了　或是最终横尸荒野了
if I go missing,anything,if I wind up dead,
那封信就会被公开
that letter is to be unsealed...
然后他们会发现和我有牵连的线索都是死胡同
And they will find cold trails that lead nowhere near me.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
如果调查你的政府探员
If a government agent
被发现浮尸于
who was looking into you is found floating
洛杉矶某条河里或者任何你计划的地方
in the L.A. River,or whatever else you have planned,
将军　你也不会有好日子过
your life,General,will change dramatically.
会有媒体的质疑报道和监视
There will be questions,media coverage and surveillance,
你和公司所做得一切
and whatever you and the Company are trying to do next
和你的小把戏
with your little Laos game,
或者是你们计划的东西
or whatever else you have planned,
都将暴露于众目睽睽之下
it'll be next to impossible with thousands of eyes on you.
好吧　请离我远点
Okay? So back off of me.
你不是
You are not
第一个想企图扳倒我的人了
the first person to attempt something like this.
大多数我习惯称同仁的
Most of the others I now fondly call my colleagues.
都学着
They've learned to put
转移自己的兴趣关注其他的事情
their determination and focus to better use,
并得到了更好的补偿
and with far greater compensation.
你看错人了
Wrong guy.
走着瞧
We'll see.
亲爱的怀特先生　鉴于不可预知的情况
"Dear Mr. White,due to unforeseen circumstances,
我很遗憾地告知您　我不能再
"I regret to inform you that I will no longer be able
为伽特公司效力了
"to perform services at GATE.
我对您所提供的机会表示感谢
"I thank you for this opportunity.
如果这让您陷入难堪的境地
"I'm deeply sorry
为此我只能深表歉意
"if this places you in a difficult position.
但我现在实在无能为力  自身难保了
"I have simply not been able to escape these circumstances.
再次感谢您所提供的绝好机会
Thank you for the wonderful,enriching opportunity..."
等等　等等　等等...
Blah,blah,blah,blah,blah.
这样写像你的口气吗
Does it sound like you?
像的
Yeah.
好的
Good. Yeah.
听我说
Look,
我不知道你是谁
I don't even know who you are,okay?
让我走吧
Just let me go...
闭嘴
Shut up.
你是不是想知道
And you wondered
我是怎么成为东北区的销售冠军的
how I got to be the top salesman in the northeast region.
对不起  行么
Sorry,okay?
对不起
Sorry.
以此为戒吧
Consider this a warning.
老不死的蒂博格
Old Teddy Bagwell
可能是库萨县的人渣
may be Coosa County trash,
但是科尔・普发是个人才
but Cole Pfeiffer's a man of refinement.
事实上  他是伽特公司的
One of the Gate Corporation's
顶尖销售人才
tippy-top sellers,as a matter of fact.
请进我的办公室
Step into my office.
应该有一个8乘10大小的房间
Well,there should be a room-- eight by ten.
惠斯勒所指的入口
Whistler's point of entry.
那是壁橱
That's a closet.
不是的
No,it's not.
汤力水加柠檬
Tonic and lime,please.
谢谢
thank you.
我简直是活在噩梦里
I'm in the middle of this nightmare.
不知道你能不能帮帮我
I wonder if you could help me.
这是我22岁的表妹的的单身派对
It's my 22-year-old cousin's bachelorette party.
那有什么可为难的
That's hardly the salt mines.
听我说
Wait for it.
我们在玩寻宝游戏
There's a scavenger hunt,
我们组派我去
and my team has tasked me
拍一张胖老头住的高级套房的照片
with getting a photograph in a whale's suite.
我像胖老头吗
I'm a whale?
你有这么一个恐怖的保镖
With a very scary bodyguard
戴这么高级的手表
and a very gorgeous watch.
你想在我的房间照张相?
And you want to take a picture in my room?
我知道这个请求实在冒昧唐突
And I realize it's a completely inappropriate request,
但他们已经怨我太扫他们的兴了
but they're already calling me a wet blanket.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我怕是爱莫能助了
I just can't help you.
如果我请求你呢
What if I said "please"?
我真的有点绝望了
I'm actually a little desperate.
祝你好运
Best of luck.
这位先生请客
Drinks are on the gentleman.
祝你玩得高兴
Have a nice day.
你也是
You,too.
不要往心里去
Don't take it personally.
你不是他喜欢的类型
You're not his type.
就在你坐下之前
Right before you sat down,
他还问我是不是想去找乐子
he asked me if I liked to party.
-绝对不行　-拜托了
-Absolutely not! No way! -Oh,come on.
为了集体牺牲一下下嘛
Take one for the team.
玛丽克鲁兹不会知道的
Maricruz will never know.
我真想掐断他的脖子
I'm gonna snap his neck.
到他房间　呆上两分钟就离开如何?
Get to his room,stay two minutes,then leave,all right?
去他房里待上两分钟就走  行么
好好 　同时呢? 　在电梯里?
Yeah,yeah,and in the meantime,what? In the elevator?
佯装你不是那种很随便的人　然后玩玩他
Just play hard to get,you know,and then let him nuzzle
让他嗯啊嗯啊...
a little bit. Whoa,whoa...!
嘿　我们还能有什么选择?
Hey,whoa! What option we got?
说啊　我们还能有什么选择?
Come on,man. What option we got?
你倒是说一个出来啊
Give me one.
你不能　给你
You can't. Here.
继续　后面没什么
Go ahead. There's nothing back there.
了解
I know.
有什么锋利点的东西么?
Do we have anything sharp?
你听说锡拉值多少?
So,what are you hearing,uh,Scylla is worth,huh?
我听说
Me,I'm hearing
值上百万
millions.
别人怎么告诉的你来着
Is that a rough ballpark
大约是个什么价钱?
in terms of what you,uh... what you've been told?
瞧我们发现什么了?
What do we have here?
你最好退后
You'd better back up.
你　我　还有一个黑洞
You and me and a dark hole.
老规矩　小白脸  你走先
Just like old times,Pretty,you first.
今天在赌场手气咋样呀?
How are the chips falling for you?
最后一块钱也买啤酒了
Spent my last buck on the beer.
在赌城破产了你该怎么办呢?
What are the options when you're broke in Vegas?
我想我得想点生财之道了  你说呢
I guess I got to work that out,huh?
假如你不必再为生计发愁呢?
What if you didn't have to?
以我的财力  或许可以
I may have a little business
给你指一条明路
to throw your way.
什么样的明路?
What kind?
很快活逍遥的那种...
The easy kind...
轻轻松松我就付你1000美元
with a $1,000 payout.
你的法国白兰地呢?
What's your cognac?
我从没拥有过
I've never had it.
我套房里有瓶200年陈的
I've got a 200-year-old bottle in my suite.
一起吧
Join me.
这是你我两人世界中
This is private business.
一次亲密的交易
Between men.
他们就来了
They're on their way up.
准备
Get ready.
我爱死它了　猛男
I love it-- Mr. Macho Man.
接下来呢
What's next?
我不知道　你怎么不自己去搞明白呢
I don't know,why don't you figure it out?
你我合作  到此为止
I'm done helping you.
貌似有些人陷入了
Sounds like someone's caught
消极怠工的状态里了
in the old captivity of negativity.
还是我来给你的脑袋瓜子提提神吧
Let's get you in a more affirmative mindset.
下一步该怎么办
What's next?
我要把你锁这屋里
I think I'm gonna lock you in this room.
然后你就被捕了
And then,you're gonna be arrested
关回到福克斯河监狱
and taken back to Fox River.
你怎么计划...
Just how do you plan on...
你们根本不清楚自己在做什么蠢事!
y'all have no idea what you're doing.
斯科菲尔德  没有我你成不了事的
Scofield,you can't do this without me.
赛尔夫马上到
Self's on his way.
记住我的话!
Mark my words!
我收到了你留下的暗号
Got your message.
你们根本不清楚自己在做什么蠢事!
Y'all have no idea what you're doing!
谢谢　阿历克斯
Thanks,Alex.
伟大的城市
Great city.
是哦
I guess so.
那就是维加斯的魅力所在
That's the thing about Vegas.
没人会对你评头论足
Doesn't judge you.
可以尽情放纵  任你逍遥快活
Any form of pleasure is acceptable here.
我没疯吧　这酒里居然有李子味儿
Am I crazy,or is there a note of plum in there?
也许有吧
Maybe.
坐吧
Have a seat.
你提供服务吗
Did you serve?
为谁服务
Serve who?
在军队里
In the military.
你看起来像美军陆战队员
You look like a Devil Dog.
没有  我从来没有参过军
No,sir,I've never been in the service before.
下载状态良好
Filling up nice.
苏克雷一定很接近了
Sucre must be in close proximity.
很可能正在擦着防晒油呢
Getting oiled,most likely.
在越南度过了一个半的服役期
One and half tours in Vietnam.
在顺化一带被自己人误伤
Purple Heart
获得过紫心勋章[凡是在战斗中负伤都发]
in a friendly fire exchange near Hue.
我很遗憾
Sorry to hear it.
我从顺化服役期中学到的
What I learned at Hue,
虽然弥足珍贵  但也让我付出了高昂的代价
though valuable,also cost me a great deal.
尤其是
Specifically...
腹股沟上层3平方英寸的大腿肉
three square inches of upper groin thigh meat.
还有随之失去的
And with that...
我的生殖和性交能力
my reproductive and sexual function.
所...所以  你不能...
So... so you can't...
"西班牙"先生  请允许我向您引见我的妻子
Mr. Villalobos,I'd like you to meet my wife.
我是阿莱克萨
I'm Alexa.
你想让我干你的老婆?
You want me to bang your wife?
我会付你1000块
And I'm gonna pay you $1,000.
再等一分钟
He's got a minute.
我就去找他
Then I'm going after him.
设备复制到那张卡了吗
Did it copy the card?
复制到了
Yep.
好的  下载吧
All right,download that.
你有5分钟
You got five minutes.
他的老婆在上面
His wife was up there.
然后呢
And...?
就当这一切从没在这发生过
It stays in Vegas.
嘿　伙计们
Uh,hey,guys.
我去方便一下
I'm gonna go hit the head,and I'll be out
就出去一会儿  行吗
in a minute,all right?
哦也!
Yes.
两个...两个回合
Two... two... two pulls.
两回合  他连续赢了
Two pulls,and he won the progressive.
他死哪去了
Where the hell is he?
我去找他
I'll go get him.
格伦先生
Mr. Glenn.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
让我们打开天窗说亮话
It was made clear
我们不再欢迎你涉足
you were never again welcome
任何一家内华达州的赌场
in any Nevada gaming establishment.
等一下  他们告诉我只以5年为限...
Wait,wait,uh,I was told there was only a five-year...
我们从未对你这么承诺过
No such thing was said to you.
那玩意是干什么用的  是游戏主机的
What's that do? It's a battery pack
一个电池组
for a video game console.
你得买个新的了
You'll need to buy a new one.
我已把卡的内容下载到我的本本里了
I already downloaded the card onto my laptop,
而且  我可以再弄一个设备
and... and I can build another device.
你说弄一个要几个月
You said this one takes months.
我们没有几个月的时间
We don't have months.
我告诉你
You know what?
我们应该把你这混球丢在沙漠里
We ought to leave your ass in the desert.
我们把他带回洛杉矶
Let's get him back to L.A.,
然后让赛尔夫来好好修理他
and let Self sort him out.
走吧
Let's go.
看那小样儿  倒是挺能吼的
For a little guy,he has some set of lungs.
-贝里克和那女的怎样了  -都安顿好了
How's Bellick and the girl? All taken care of.
我会将蒂博格监禁起来  严加看守
I'm gonna keep T-Bag in protective custody
直到我们拿到锡拉  然后我就会让一些
until we get Scylla-- then,I'm gonna make somebody
在伊利诺斯商务部里头的人  "爽歪了"
at Illinois DOC very,very happy.
可是更重要的是
But more importantly,
房间的楼下究竟有何玄机呢
what the hell is that room downstairs?
那里没有他们可以藏那个
That's not where they keep the device
能破译锡拉设备的地方 对不对
that decodes Scylla,is it?
没有
No.
那只是蒂博格自己认为有而已
That's just what T-Bag thought.
通向锡拉之路只能从这个位置出发
The road to Scylla only begins down there.
这里就是我们逮住蒂博格的房间
This is the room where we've got T-Bag now.
只要翻过南墙
Just past the south wall,
那里有个隧道入口  那个入口
there's an access tunnel that runs
直通向外面300码的地方
for about 300 yards or so.
穿过那里  我们就进去了
We get through that,we're in.
那里就是我们能破译锡拉的所在了
That's where we can decode Scylla.
还有这就是克兰兹将军办公室
And this is the building
所在的那幢楼
where General Krantz's office is.
-对头咯  -我今天才刚去过那里
-There you go. -I was there today,
可是我得提醒你  那里的保全系统
but I have to tell you,the security
很好很强大
in that place is unbelievable.
根据设计图
According to the blueprint,
建筑的底部结构是完全暴露的
the substructure is completely exposed.
这用不了24小时
It shouldn't take more than 24 hours
-就可以去到那里  -这只用花24小时吗
-to get in there. -It's only gonna take 24 hours?
我们只要先把最后一张卡搞到手就行了
All we have to do is get that last card first.
那么  基于目前我已经破译的部分
Well,based on what I've deciphered so far,
我们需要随时可以进入伽特公司
we're gonna need around-the-clock access to GATE,
现在就开始行动
starting immediately.
如果你能帮我们弄到制服和证件的话
If you can get us some suits and IDs,
我们可以像国税局审计员一样进去
we could go in there as IRS agents
审查账目  我是指审查
auditing the books-- I mean,considering
他们在进行何种不法勾当
the kind of racket they're running,
瞒天过海  天衣无缝
nobody would have a problem believing that.
你能做到吗
Can you make that happen?
是的  我能做到
Yeah,I could do it.
在垃圾桶下面
It's under the can.
喂
Hello?
我们是一条道上混的
We have a lot in common.
是吗  你是谁
Yeah,who is this?
另一个参与你们群雄逐鹿的利益集团
Just another interested party in what you're up to.
是吗  你指什么
Yeah,what's that?
锡拉
Scylla.
打开那个信封
Open the envelope.
[惠斯勒那本鸟类书的部分残页]
我手头只有77页
The pages I've got only go up to 77.
这就是补充的新设计图吗
Is this more blueprint?
我不知道
I don't know.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我不知道你们都对蒂博格干了些什么
I don't know what you've done
不过除非我亲眼看到他
with Bagwell,but unless I see him,
否则你们就拿不到剩下的书页
you're not getting the rest of the pages.
是吗
Is that right?
把电话给我
Give me that.
你是何方神圣?
Who is this?
你好啊  迈克
Hello,Michael.